You have entered the DAO section.
Decentralized autonomous organizations, also known as DAOs,
are built around rules encoded as a computer program
and controlled by the organization's members.
A key element to a DAO
is that it has no central leadership and decisions must be made from the bottom-up,
ruled by the community as a whole.
How will the world of NFTs be influenced by DAOs?
Dolce & Gabbana, DogeCrown, 2021 purchased by RED DAO
Currently, one of the most popular types of DAOs
is focused on collecting and investing in creative work for a specific industry.
The most popular fashion DAO to date is the RED DAO.
The RED DAO was created to support and invest in the future of fashion.
Made up of 40+ members from all over the world,
RED DAO has collected hundreds of virtual works
and has also invested in a handful of leading web3 platforms,
such as UNXD, RSTLSS and The Fabricant.
In 2021, the RED DAO made headlines after it purchased one of Dolce & Gabbana’s first-ever NFTs,
the Doge Crown, for almost $1.3 million in Ether.
Supporters of DAOs
believe that these organizations have the ability to further empower creators, designers and artists alike.
DAOs create new investment opportunities for its members
and the creators they bring into these communities and beyond.
The DAO rulebook can help to democratize work, creative process and more.
It will be interesting to see how DAOs develop in the next chapter of Web 3.0.