You have entered the DUAL LIFE section.
Although NFTs are considered unique digital assets,
some companies have been offering NFTs
alongside in-person experiences or real life items, creating a dual use.
METAPIGEON, JEFF STAPLE in partnership with RTFKT, 2021
Moving away from art and into fashion,
the fashion industry sees NFTs as a way to certify authenticity
and, simultaneously,
create the ability for buyers to wear their real-world clothes in the metaverse.
Jeff Staple is a streetwear pioneer who launched the Nike SB Pigeon Dunk in 2005
that sparked riots in New York City.
Mr. Staple had the foresight to see the parallels
between the rise of streetwear and the NFT market.
He released a limited edition drop that brought the hype of the sneaker community into the metaverse.
In partnership with RTFKT, he launched METAPIGEON.
The METAPIGEON K-MINUS dropped in May 2021
and included a virtual chromatic edition of the shoe
and a physical version that was delivered to buyers in tandem.
Each shoe had an edition of 100 that sold out in minutes.
CHFTY Pizzas
Alongside the fashion world,
there has been increased interest from the hospitality industry to leverage NFT technology.
World renowned chefs Tom Colicchio and Spike Mendelsohn
dropped a collection of 2777 NFTs in March of 2022.
Each CHFTY Pizza owner is given exclusive access to digital masterclasses,
in-person pop-ups, custom kitchen accessories and apparel,
as well as access to a community of chefs, food enthusiasts and collectors alike.
Moving on from the physical versus digital twin aspect that we see with the Jeff Staple sneaker,
the NFT ownership now offers up a world of experiences.