You have entered the healthcare section.
While many connect NFTs to the world of art,
another way to leverage this technology can be seen in the healthcare data market.
DNA NFT sample, Aimedis
Due to the fragmented U.S. healthcare system,
NFT technology can help to consolidate and organize a patient’s data across different healthcare providers
into one unique and safe digital file.
The technology would pull a patient’s data across platforms
and help the patient and doctors track diagnosis and tests throughout their lifetime.
In addition to this,
the patient would be able to own their healthcare data,
ensuring that medical and healthcare companies are not selling the data.
Aimedis, an eHealth platform utilizing blockchain technology, launched in 2020.
This healthcare platform combines eHealth applications,
such as health records, video chat with doctors, appointments, prescriptions, and emergency records.
This is all done on a unique medical and scientific-pharmaceutical NFT data marketplace,
which displays all relevant operations in a private blockchain, visible and transparent to the patient.
Here we see an image of an DNA NFT cover sample which patients
and their doctors can access easily through the Aimedis platform.
Using blockchain technology,
Aimedis users will be able to easily track their medical records across different healthcare institutions.
Using NFT technology, Aimedis will offer
staking, governance, medical DeFi and social token functionalities.
It is expected that this technology,
will see a longer opportunity for adoption in the U.S.
as a result of the country’s convoluted healthcare system.