You have entered the Origins section.
Before we get into the different industries and themes we see playing in the world of NFTs,
we wanted to give you some background on its origins.
Here are two examples of some of the first NFTs on the market
that continue to remain relevant and are considered integral to the NFT origin story.
175 CRYPTOPUNKS WITH MEDICAL MASK, CRYPTOPUNKS, 2017
In 2017, two software developers created an experimental crypto art project dubbed CryptoPunks.
Using an algorithm, the project generated 10,000 unique digital images.
The images were originally released for free,
but recently some have sold for upwards of $7 million.
CryptoPunks is widely regarded as blockchain’s first foray into cryptoart
and the images have garnered a large collector following.
What you see here is a grid of the 175 CryptoPunks that exist wearing a medical mask,
which shows how quickly art and culture impact each other in the digital world.
CRYPTOKITTIES, 2017
Outside of the art market, NFTs have taken off just as fast in the gaming industry.
CryptoKitties is a blockchain game developed by Dapper Labs on the Ethereum network.
The game explores the concept of digital scarcity.
It allows players to collect, make, purchase and sell virtual cats as NFTs.
Once a CryptoKitty is made and minted, it becomes its own NFT,
available for trade or sale.
As CryptoKitties breed,
their offspring’s appearance and cattributes are determined by each parent’s 265-bit genome
and an element of chance, leading to four billion possible genetic variations.
In December 2018,
a massive spike in transactions caused a slow down on the Ethereum network.
By 2018,
CryptoKitties was spun out from Dapper Labs
and made into its own company with an initial investment round of $12million.
CryptoKitties range in price from $8 to $140,000.