You have entered the advertising section.
NFTs have been used to help marketing efforts
from new product launches to customer engagement opportunities.
See how big brands are jumping in.
NFT Taco Art by Taco Bell, 2021
When you think of Taco Bell and NFTs
you might not see the direct correlation between the brand and the technology.
However, in March of 2021, to celebrate the return of potatoes to the Taco Bell menu,
the fast food chain launched a collection of taco-themed NFTs that sold out in 30 minutes.
All proceeds of the NFT sales
went on to support the Live Más Scholarship within the Taco Bell Foundation.
The collection was made up of five pieces of art
inspired by the Spicy Potato Soft Taco and the Crunchy Taco,
with five editions of each piece at the price of a Taco Bell menu item.
Each of the NFT purchasers
were surprise-gifted with free Taco Bell for a year,
in the form of a $500 eGift card.
Taco Bell’s goal for this NFT activation
was to merge their fans’ passion for the brand and food with a digital format.
It proved to be successful.
In addition to customer engagement and product launch awareness,
the NFT collection enables Taco Bell to earn 0.1% of every resale of each NFT.
Some of these images have sold on the resale market for upwards of $18,000.
The Heritage NFT Collection by Budweiser, 2021
Another large brand to enter the world of digital assets
was Anheuser-Busch InBev’s beer brand Budweiser.
In November of 2021, the beverage giant launched its debut NFT collection.
The Heritage NFT Collection is composed of 1,936 unique digital cans
representing 1936, the year the first Budweiser can was created.
It was made available to consumers of legal drinking age via two different token types at launch
the Core Heritage Cans and the Gold Heritage Cans.
Each Heritage Collection NFT is a one-of-a-kind digital asset
generated from designs across Budweiser’s history.
Among the 1,936 tokens to be released,
1,900 are Core Heritage tokens
which were each priced at $499
and 36 are Gold Heritage tokens, which were each priced at $999.
While most companies that use NFTs for marketing purposes
give the tokens away for free or at a very low cost,
this is an example of a large organization stepping awayfrom the typical NFT strategies,
typically centered around product launches or brand awareness.
Instead they have leveraged the history of an iconic brand
and engaged with super fans who want to own a piece of the brand’s history.
Interestingly enough,
Budweiser has since launched other NFT drops
and continues to sell the NFTs at a higher price point.