You have entered the Collectibles section.
NFT technology is easily made into one-of-a-kind trading cards and memorabilia.
Here are some examples of how companies are tapping into this space,
leveraging notoriety and scarcity in the digital space.
US OPEN, 2021
In 2021, the US Open debuted its first ever NFT collection.
The collectibles ranged from limited edition ticket stubs to “golden ace” tokens.
These offered in-person experiences with tennis champions such as Venus Williams and Andy Roddick,
giving fans another way to engage with, and commemorate the experience.
After the sale, the NFT marketplace Bitski saw that this NFT collection
brought an entirely new community of people into the world of NFTs
as a majority of sales were from first-time buyers.
PATIENT PANDA, VEEFRIENDS, 2021
VeeFriends is a Gary Vaynerchuk NFT project,
comprised of 10,255 hand drawn characters.
The project aims to create a meaningful community
and real life value around intellectual property.
They do this by adding utility to these tokens,
such as access to VeeCon
an annual conference that Mr. Vaynerchuk plans to produce for the next three years.
The VeeFriends collection was launched in May 2021 and by October 1st,
the original hand-drawn artworks made their Christie's debut,
resulting in a seven figure sale.
The collection of characters represent human traits
that Mr. Vaynerchuk most admires and which he believes will lead to happiness and success.
A portion of funds from token royalties will be donated to charities,
as well as five free scholarship tokens
that give owners access to learn from Mr. Vaynerchuk and his professional network.
To offset the environmental impact,
VeeFriends will be making contributions towards decentralized autonomous organizations
to benefit renewable energy and support the Eth 2.0 proof of stake development.