You have entered the evolutive section.
NFTs that change and evolve over the course of time.
Eroding and Reforming Bust of Rome (One Year), Daniel Arsham, 2021
In lieu of creating a permanent digital work of art,
the contemporary artist Daniel Arsham created a time-based evolutive NFT
that evolves and transforms over the course of one year.
Released on May 22, 2021, the work of art will exist until May 22, 2022.
With Eroding and Reforming Bust of Rome (One Year),
Mr. Arsham introduced a concept never before seen in the NFT world.
While we see most artists and institutions creating NFTs to exist for eternity,
Mr. Arsham approached this project with a finite timeline
while also creating an NFT that can ultimately change over the course of its existence.
This approach to NFT creation can be utilized for various different applications of the technology,
from artwork to play to earn to healthcare and more.