You have entered the Heritage section.
Many people consider NFTs to be new-age digital artworks
that are inspired by and created in the 21st century.
There are several museums and institutions that create NFTs from historical works of art,
allowing new collectors to own a piece of art history.
THE GREAT WAVE by Katsushika Hokusai,
LaCollection in partnership with the BRITISH MUSEUM, 2021
The art world was one of the fastest industries to adopt the use of NFTs,
since they serve as a certificate of authenticity for digital artifacts and their scarcity.
These unique certificates are attached to digital images.
As NFTs are traded and tracked indefinitely through the use of blockchain technology,
it is a failsafe way to confirm a piece’s provenance.
With each sale of an NFT artwork,
the original artist receives a small percentage of each resale transaction.
As a result, as long as the artwork exists,
NFTs can enhance the earning power of each piece of art for perpetuity.
On September 30, 2021,
LaCollection launched its first NFT platform dedicated to museums and art institutions
in partnership with the British Museum.
The platform specializes in certifying masterpieces
and functions as a certificate of authenticity signed by partner institutions.
The work you see in front of you is “Under the Wave off Kanagawa,”
also known as “The Great Wave” by Katsushika Hokusai.
Owned by the British Museum, from the series,
“Thirty-six Views of Mount Fuji” made in 1831.
On LaCollection,
patrons are able to buy NFT versions of historical works of art
like “The Great Wave” in small editions of 10.
The minting of this physical work of art gives the general public
an opportunity to own their very own version of art history
and creates a passive revenue stream for the museum.