You have entered the tickets and memberships section.
NFTs create a new version of tickets and membership cards
that go beyond buying the physical tickets or a unique membership card,
something that lives in the digital world and can’t be lost.
Flyfish Club
Flyfish Club is the world’s first member’s only dining club
where membership is purchased on the blockchain as a NFT
and owned by the token-holder to gain access to the dining club,
along with various culinary, cultural and social experiences.
As the first of its kind, Flyflsh Club is focused around utility.
Members will have access to an exclusive dining club
that’s curated by award-winning chefs and hospitality experts.
Never before has a restaurant, venue or club
combined private member dining experiences
with blockchain technology, converting a membership into an asset.
The membership requires no application or recurring annual fees.
As an NFT,
membership can be used to enjoy the club or if desired,
it can be sold, transferred or leased to others at the owner's choice
leveraging the unique blockchain technology to the owner’s advantage.