You have entered the Sustainability section.
The production of an average single-edition NFT
is equivalent to driving a petrol car for 1,000 kilometers,
hence, the environmental impact of NFT minting is something we cannot ignore.
How are people addressing this?
DEEPER MEDITATIONS #6, MEMO AKTEN, 2018
For the first time ever, thanks to NFT technology,
digital artists are able to sustain a living by making art.
But we cannot talk about NFTs without addressing its negative impact on the environment.
Every NFT that is minted becomes a part of the blockchain network and increases carbon emissions.
Blockchain technology requires a significant amount of gas
as well as several kilotons of e-waste per year.
Because of this,
people have been advocating for more transparency around the impact of each NFT.
Some suggest that NFTs should provide ballpark figures
and advice regarding each NFTs ecological impact
and should be made compulsory for all marketplaces.
Those who oppose the compulsory impact information
argue that blockchain eliminates traditional banking methods.
It doesn’t require offices full of employees and web servers,
which have a larger impact on the environment,
so they believe that it’s simply not necessary.
Creative technologist and doctorate in AI Memo Akten
is a crypto artist championing a more eco-friendly world for NFTs.
He exclusively uses the proof-of-stake consensus algorithm
as it requires millions less in energy than the normal proof-of-work algorithm.
As a result of its impact,
Ethereum also plans to change to the proof-of-stake consensus algorithm
to ensure that its algorithms are more environmentally friendly.
We have selected this piece,
Deeper Meditations #6 from Memo’s 2018 collection,
which is a self portrait that explores the minds of an artificial and biological neural network.
Together with many other pieces in this exhibition,
we explore how generative art takes on a life of its own.