Intercontinental Hotels and Resorts has
expanded its partnership with British
artist Claire Luxton to create
a collection of unique NFPs with luxury
travel benefits,
a first for both Claire
and the Intercontinental Hotels
and Resorts brand.
Each of the ten NFTs in the collection is
inspired by the beauty of global travel,
integrating the natural flora and fauna
signature of the artists work
to illustrate the Intercontinental brands,
storied heritage and far
flung destinations.
Motifs are brought to life through
animation, including the blue and yellow
Maccour, which represents the first
Intercontinental hotel in Bellem, Brazil,
and the Panther Chameleon Spotlighting
Intercontinental Resort Mauritius
on Balaclava Bay.
Members of IHG One Rewards IHG Hotels
and Resorts awardwinning loyalty program
will be able to use their points
to exclusively bid on a number of the NFTs
following their exhibition in November.
Each NFT also comes with a one year
Intercontinental Ambassador status,
which provides exceptional benefits
and elevated recognition in the entirely
redesigned IHG One Rewards program.
The NFT also grants a onenight stay
at the new Intercontinental Rome
ambassadorI Palace, opening in 2020.
Intercontinental Hotels and Resorts is
part of IHG Hotels and Resorts,
one of the world's leading hotel
companies, with 17 hotel brands
and over 60 destinations worldwide.