You have entered the Real Estate section.
While we continue to live in the real world,
many companies and individuals have begun to build their presence in the metaverse.
Currently, the metaverse real estate market is as hot as a corner unit condo in Manhattan.
You can even visit an office, shop at a store and clean your house in the virtual world these days.
DECENTRALAND FOUNDATION, 2015
A dilemma met by many NFT collectors was
”how do I display or even use my collection?”
Enter Decentraland,
a 3D virtual reality world where users can create their own avatar, buy land parcels,
interact with other users, attend concerts and exhibitions,
build their own homes, and so much more.
Users are beginning to form communities in Decentraland,
which are growing all the time in this ever-evolving virtual world.
Each land parcel in Decentraland is an NFT and is unique to its own plot.
On these plots of land, users can build their own spaces and exhibit their wider NFT collections.
Over the last year several corporations have started to build their own presence in the metaverse.
Sotheby’s built a virtual replica of their new Bond Street location in Decentraland
and more recently, the real estate investment company Republic Realm
purchased 259 land parcels on which it will build a virtual shopping district called Metajuku,
named after Tokyo’s Harajuku.
Decentraland is one of the fastest growing real estate marketplaces for the metaverse.