You have entered the Generative section.
Generative NFT artwork is a work of art that is created in whole, or in part, by an AI algorithm.
The algorithm typically pulls from a set number of features listed to create one unique work,
without any human assistance.
BORED APE YACHT CLUB #8817 - Gold Party Ape
Bored Ape Yacht Club, also known as Bored Ape,
is one of the most well known Web 3.0 brands today.
This collection of over 10,000 NFTs is individually generated by a computer algorithm
built by its four founders.
As a result of the series’s fame and increased demand, in 2021,
the Bored Ape Yacht Club surpassed Cryptopunks as the highest priced NFTs and as of 2022,
the collection’s sales have totaled over $1 Billion,
making it one of the highest valued NFT projects on the market to date.
This seemingly conventional NFT series grew in popularity due to several factors:
Firstly, unlike most art NFTs,
upon purchase of a Bored Ape NFT, the buyer owns the full intellectual property of the artwork,
thus creating potential for easy marketing and branding opportunities.
Secondly, this NFT series was quickly adopted by celebrities and influencers
and popularized over social media.
Many owners began using their Bored Ape as their profile picture
which in turn created a scarcity mindset around the works and turned it into a status symbol.
Thirdly, the Bored Ape Yacht Club has resulted in several very popular offshoots
which were only available to Bored Ape owners,
ranging from the Mutant Ape Yacht Club to the Bored Ape Kennel Club.
Due to the huge popularity of this series,
Adidas Group purchased a Bored Ape in September of 2021.
And the Bored Ape Yacht Club partnered with Rolling Stone magazine
to produce a limited edition zine in November of 2021.
CHROMIE SQUIGGLE #0, ARTBLOCKS, SNOWFRO, 2020
Generative art began in the 1960s but not all creations see the light.
Artists cherry pick the best of them from a variety of outputs their algorithm generates.
Erick Calderon, artist, developer and tinkerer, known as Snowfro,
created the ArtBlocks.io platform in a way that forces the artist
to accept every output their algorithm generates.
You can tweak and modify the script and settings until you are comfortable with the result,
but you are not able to discard any.
This method elevates the level of algorithmic execution.
Pieces are complex and compellingly different but still beautiful
and obviously belong to the same algorithm.
The system creates static images, 3D models or interactive experiences
that are stored immutably on the Ethereum blockchain.
This is Chromie Squiggle #0, made from what one day will be a total of 10,000 mints.
Each is like Snowfro’s personal signature.
It is the largest project currently on the Art Blocks.io platform,
and people can select “live view” to see the colors moving through the Chromie.