You have entered the Film section.
While movie stars and celebrities alike are some of the biggest NFT collectors,
how is the business of Hollywood entering into the world of NFTs?
What are the use cases for NFTs in tinseltown?
ZERO CONTACT, VUELE, 2021
One of the newest industries to tap into the world of NFTs is film.
In 2021, the film “Zero Contact” launched as an NFT via CurrencyWorks on Vuele,
a platform for watching and collecting limited edition films and NFT content.
Film NFTs align with the movie memorabilia market and bring this industry into the digital space.
Like all NFTs, movie NFTs can be viewed, collected, bought, sold and traded.
Bidding began on September 24, 2021.
The one-of-one Zero Contact platinum edition NFT sold for $56,860
and the elite edition sold for a total of $36,575.
In addition to the original sale,
CurrencyWorks receives ongoing royalties every time these NFTs are bought and sold.
While “Zero Contact” was initially launched as a direct-to-consumer film,
the film will be widely released later this year.
Aria, Co-created by Alessandro Michele and Floria Sigismondi for Gucci
For its debut NFT, the Italian luxury fashion house Gucci minted an NFT fashion film.
This unique artwork was conceived using digital animation drawn from Gucci Aria,
their Spring 2021 campaign film,
co-directed by Gucci’s Creative Director Alessandro Michele
and award-winning photographer and director Floria Sigismondi.
It was sold at a special auction at Christie’s
and all proceeds of the sale were donated to UNICEF USA.
The artwork underlying the NFT speaks to Aria’s overarching message:
a yearning to bloom and flourish after the shadow of winter has passed.
Like the Zero Contact NFT film,
this film lends itself to the idea of engaging with brand enthusiasts and collectors.