You have entered the Dow Jones section.
Currently, Dow Jones' foray into NFTs.
BARRON'S 100 YEARS, 2021
In 2021, to commemorate the 100 year anniversary of Barron’s magazine,
the financial publication minted its first and centennial covers
on SuperRare, Ethereum’s art marketplace.
Journalist and historian Kenneth Pringle
combed the Barron’s archives for stories from the past that are being told once again.
For example, we saw a version of the GameStop phenomenon in the 1920s,
when a supermarket was being sold short by a number of Wall Street investment firms.
Using the research and coverage in Barron's centennial issue,
the NFT-minted cover is a visual interpretation of those dualities.
Younger investors are getting into the financial market through new platforms and avenues,
and the NFT is just one of those growing markets they’re putting their money behind.
WSJ FIRST STIPPLE NFT, 2021
The Wall Street Journal’s first stipple (or ‘hedcut’) appeared on its front page in 1979.
Named for a drawing technique used to illustrate currency
— stippling — the style has become a Journal signature,
hand-drawn to this day by a team of artists who spend four to five hours creating each image.
At The Wall Street Journal’s Tech Live Conference in October 2021,
an attendee won the Journal’s very first NFT-minted stipple.
The winner was able to choose from 6 different stipple images
and ultimately chose a stipple of a rolodex to be minted.