You have entered the Authentication section.
In a wildly unregulated market,
there has been a proliferation of unauthorized NFT art.
These range from people pretending to be an artist,
to metaverse designers making big brand products without licensing.
JOIN THE ARMY, SHOLIM, 2014
While NFTs serve as a certificate of authenticity for digital artifacts,
hackers have exploited the burgeoning market and those who are not crypto-literate.
In 2021, the Serbian artist Milos Rajkovic, also known as Sholim,
was caught by surprise when he was alerted by social media that he had an NFT sale of 122 works of art.
It was indeed copies of his work,
but it was not Mr. Rajkovic making the sales.
Mr. Rajkovic alerted the platform and the sale
was pulled down and he has since sought guidance from a copyright lawyer.
Due to the nature of a decentralized crypto market,
it may be difficult to identify fraud and move forward with recourse
when the origin point does not have a trusted verification source.
On the flip side,
because records are immutable,
when a proper verification system is in place,
it is increasingly easier to track the history of genuine provenance.